Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about something that's very common in high
我是Catherine，今天我们要讨论一个在英语国家高中里非常常见的话题。
schools all across the English speaking world.
这个话题在英语国家的高中里非常普遍。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going to talk a little bit about sexual education or also called sex ed.
今天我们要聊一聊性教育，也叫sex ed。
So you may be asking yourself what exactly this means.
你可能在想这到底是什么意思。
So let's take a look at this word on Vocabulary Preview.
那我们来看看词汇预览中的这个词。
Okay, so more commonly than not we're going to hear the phrase sex ed, E-D.
好的，我们更常听到的是sex ed这个短语，E-D。
That stands for education.
这代表education（教育）。
This is basically a class or a training about sexuality and safety when it comes to these
这基本上是一门关于性行为和安全问题的课程或培训。
issues.
涉及这些方面。
That's right.
没错。
So as you said, this is a very common class that is part of the school curriculum in English
正如你所说，这是英语国家学校课程中非常常见的一门课。
speaking countries.
在英语国家很常见。
I think maybe students are about 16 to 15, 16 years old when they get sex ed.
我想学生大概在15到16岁时会上性教育课。
We had it when I was about 13, 14.
我大概13、14岁时上过。
13, 14.
13、14岁。
So it all depends.
所以这取决于具体情况。
Now many countries don't really have this in their public schools.
现在很多国家的公立学校并没有这门课。
Other countries only have it in private schools.
有些国家只在私立学校开设。
So it's a very controversial topic about if schools should actually be teaching this.
所以关于学校是否应该教授这门课，这是一个很有争议的话题。
But we'll talk about that a little bit later on.
但我们稍后会讨论这个问题。
Why don't we take a look at today's dialogue.
我们先来看看今天的对话吧。
Let's listen to what's happening today.
我们来听听今天发生了什么。
All right, settle down everyone.
好了，大家安静下来。
As part of this school's curriculum, we'll be covering sex ed this week.
作为学校课程的一部分，这周我们将学习性教育。
Oh boy, yeah.
哦，天哪，太好了。
Now I want everyone to take this class seriously.
我希望每个人都能认真对待这门课。
Sexual education is very important and I want you to ask as many questions as you can think
性教育非常重要，我希望你们尽可能多地提问。
of.
想到什么问题就问。
Remember, there are no stupid questions here.
记住，这里没有愚蠢的问题。
Miss Carlton, what exactly is sexual education?
卡尔顿老师，性教育到底是什么？
Are you going to teach us like Kama Sutra and stuff like that?
您会教我们像《爱经》之类的东西吗？
No, Jason, that's not actually what sex ed is.
不，Jason，那并不是性教育的内容。
Basically, we will talk about sexually transmitted diseases, contraceptives, and how the male
基本上，我们会讨论性传播疾病、避孕方法，以及男性和女性身体的工作原理。
and female bodies work.
以及男性和女性身体的工作原理。
My older sister is in college and she takes what she and her friends call the pill.
我姐姐在上大学，她和她的朋友们会吃一种叫避孕药的东西。
I never really understood what that is, but I know it has to do with sex or something.
我一直不太明白那是什么，但我知道它和性有关。
Good point, Jason.
问得好，Jason。
This will be the topic of our first class, contraceptives.
这将是我们第一节课的主题——避孕方法。
As you mentioned, the pill is one of the many that exist.
正如你提到的，避孕药是其中一种。
The birth control pill is taken daily by a woman in order to prevent unwanted pregnancy,
女性每天服用避孕药来防止意外怀孕。
but it does not protect her from contracting STDs from an infected person.
但它不能保护她免受感染者的性传播疾病感染。
Another popular method is using condoms.
另一种流行的方法是使用安全套。
This is probably the best method if you have sex, since it not only prevents a woman from
如果你有性生活，这可能是最好的方法，因为它不仅能防止女性怀孕。
getting pregnant, but also protects you from STDs.
还能保护你免受性传播疾病的感染。
Yes, Jason?
怎么了，Jason？
What are condoms made out of?
安全套是用什么做的？
How is it exactly that a woman gets pregnant?
女性到底是怎么怀孕的？
Condoms are usually made out of an elastic material called latex.
安全套通常由一种叫做乳胶的弹性材料制成。
As for your other question, that's a whole new class.
至于你的另一个问题，那得另开一堂课了。
Alright, we're back, so now I'm sure there are a couple of words that we didn't really
好了，我们回来了，现在我相信对话里有一些词我们不太理解。
understand there, so let's take a look at a couple of them on Language Takeaway.
所以我们来看看“语言要点”中的几个词。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
Okay, so one of the most common phrases you're going to hear when it comes to sex and safety
好的，关于性行为和性安全，你最常听到的一个短语就是性传播疾病，简称STD。
when you're having sex is sexually transmitted disease or STD.
性传播疾病，简称STD。
That's right, so the teacher actually mentioned the whole name sexually transmitted diseases
没错，老师确实提到了全称“性传播疾病”。
and also she used the acronym STDs or STD in STD.
她也用了缩写STDs或STD。
And what exactly are these STDs?
这些STD到底是什么？
Well, the key word here is disease.
嗯，关键词是“疾病”。
These are illnesses that you can get from sex.
这些是通过性行为可能染上的疾病。
So sexually transmitted means transmitted or passed on from one person to another person
所以“性传播”指的是在性行为过程中从一个人传给另一个人。
during sex and this could include any kind of diseases like AIDS or syphilis or chlamydia
这可能包括像艾滋病、梅毒、衣原体感染或淋病之类的疾病。
or gonorrhea.
或者淋病。
Those are the most famous ones.
这些是最常见的。
That's right, so sexually transmitted diseases.
没错，就是性传播疾病。
Now why don't we get into the title of our lesson today, contraceptives.
现在我们进入今天课程的主题——避孕方法。
What are these contraceptives?
这些避孕方法是什么？
Okay, so teachers are always going to explain the big difference between protection and
好的，老师总是会解释保护措施和避孕方法之间的重大区别。
contraception or contraceptives.
或者避孕方法。
Usually contraceptives have to do with getting pregnant.
通常避孕方法与怀孕有关。
If you don't want your girlfriend to get pregnant and your guy or if your girl and you don't
如果你不想让你的女朋友怀孕，或者你作为女生不想怀孕。
want to get pregnant, you take contraceptives or you use contraceptives.
你就会服用或使用避孕方法。
There are many different kinds and I think the most common kind for preventing pregnancy
有很多不同的种类，我认为预防怀孕最常见的方法。
or keep making sure you don't get pregnant is something called the pill.
或者确保你不会怀孕的方法，就是所谓的避孕药。
That's right, one of the kids said that his sister takes the pill.
没错，其中一个孩子说他姐姐在吃避孕药。
Now this is called the pill.
这就是所谓的避孕药。
Now you know that pills are any type of a capsule or little medicine that you swallow
你知道药片是任何类型的胶囊或小药丸，用水吞服。
with water.
用水送服。
But what is the pill?
但药丸是什么？
Well this is the birth control pill.
嗯，这就是避孕药。
So that's a long name.
这个名字真长。
People often in conversation just say the pill.
人们在日常对话中通常只说“药丸”。
But it's called the birth control pill and it's a pill that women take every day or some
但它被称为避孕药，是一种女性每天服用或某些
of them different times to prevent pregnancy.
在不同时间服用以防止怀孕的药丸。
So that means that you're trying not to get pregnant.
所以这意味着你试图避免怀孕。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so this is called a contraceptive.
好的，所以这被称为避孕药。
Now as you mentioned, this is a contraceptive so it will prevent you from getting pregnant.
正如你提到的，这是一种避孕药，可以防止你怀孕。
But it will not protect you and as many of you may know, the most common form of protection
但它不会保护你，而且正如许多人可能知道的，最常见的防止
against pregnancy and STDs are a little device called a condom.
怀孕和性传播疾病的方法是一种叫做避孕套的小装置。
Okay, so a condom is like you said the most common kind of protection that people use
好的，所以避孕套就像你说的，是人们最常用的一种保护措施，
and it's important because it helps you not only not get pregnant but also not get a disease.
它很重要，因为它不仅帮助你避免怀孕，还能防止感染疾病。
And so people often talk about this as being the most important kind of protection from
所以人们经常谈论这是预防
disease and pregnancy.
疾病和怀孕最重要的保护方式。
And it's basically just a cover for a man's penis and it prevents liquids being passed
它基本上就是男性阴茎的覆盖物，防止液体从
on from one person to another person.
一个人传给另一个人。
That's right and actually as you mentioned, this has to do with our next word.
没错，实际上正如你提到的，这和我们下一个词有关。
It prevents you from contracting STDs like the teacher mentioned.
它防止你感染性传播疾病，就像老师提到的那样。
So to contract an STD or to contract an illness, what does that mean?
那么，感染性传播疾病或感染疾病，这是什么意思？
Well contract is a special verb that we use when we're talking about getting a disease.
嗯，“contract”是一个特殊的动词，当我们谈论得病时使用。
You don't say I got a disease, you say I contracted it.
你不会说“我得了病”，而是说“我感染了”。
That means I got it from somewhere or someone.
意思是我从某个地方或某人那里得了病。
And that's one of the dangers of sexually transmitted diseases.
这就是性传播疾病的危险之一。
You can contract very serious diseases just by having sex.
仅仅通过性行为，你就可能感染非常严重的疾病。
Now can I say I contracted the flu?
那我能说“我感染了流感”吗？
I mean it's not incorrect but we don't really say that with the flu.
我的意思是，这不算错，但我们通常不这么说流感。
It's not a very serious illness.
它不是一种非常严重的疾病。
You say it with very serious illnesses.
你用它来形容非常严重的疾病。
So yeah I don't think you would go around saying I contracted a cold last week.
所以，我觉得你不会到处说“我上周感染了感冒”。
I got the cold.
我得了感冒。
And you wouldn't say this about cancer either because cancer is not something you get from
你也不会用这个词来形容癌症，因为癌症不是从
someone else.
别人那里得的。
But you say he contracted AIDS or he contracted gonorrhea for example.
但你会说“他感染了艾滋病”或“他感染了淋病”，例如。
Okay very good.
好的，非常好。
So as you see the spelling is actually the same as a contract like an agreement between
所以你看，拼写实际上和“合同”一样，就像公司或
a company or two people.
两个人之间的协议。
But the accent is different.
但重音不同。
A contract is an agreement to contract that what we're talking about.
“合同”是一个协议，而“感染”是我们正在讨论的。
Illnesses.
疾病。
To get.
得病。
Alright very good.
好的，非常好。
And for our final word, we're going back to condoms.
对于我们的最后一个词，我们回到避孕套。
The material that they are made out of is called latex.
它们制成的材料叫做乳胶。
Okay so latex is a very special kind of material that is like they say in the dialogue elastic.
好的，乳胶是一种非常特殊的材料，就像对话中说的，有弹性。
It's stretchy.
它有伸缩性。
And it's almost plasticky.
而且几乎像塑料。
But it's very very tough.
但它非常非常坚韧。
It's very strong and that's why they make condoms out of it.
它非常结实，所以用来做避孕套。
And I think we also see things made out of latex for example doctors when they're operating
我想我们也看到用乳胶做的东西，比如医生做手术时
they wear latex gloves.
戴乳胶手套。
That's right.
没错。
Obviously they don't want to use materials that are weak or that are thin because they
显然，他们不想使用脆弱或薄的材料，因为他们
need to protect their patients from germs.
需要保护病人免受细菌感染。
And so latex gloves and latex condoms are very very common because they are so durable.
所以乳胶手套和乳胶避孕套非常常见，因为它们非常耐用。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of interesting stuff there.
所以那里有很多有趣的内容。
Why don't we now jump on over and take a look at a couple of different phrases on Fluency
我们现在为什么不跳到“流利度构建器”部分，看看几个
Builder.
不同的短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So this first phrase is something you should be very very familiar with if you've ever
所以第一个短语，如果你曾经在美国或加拿大的教室里待过，
been in a classroom in America or Canada.
你应该非常熟悉。
Often times with younger children or with high school children people get really worked
很多时候，对于年幼的孩子或高中生，人们会变得非常激动，
up very excited.
非常兴奋。
You know kids are yelling and talking and they're giggling and they think that oh sex
你知道，孩子们在喊叫、说话、咯咯笑，他们认为性
is so funny.
很有趣。
And so the teacher always says settle down.
所以老师总是说“安静下来”。
Settle down.
安静下来。
Okay.
好的。
So if somebody tells you to settle down.
所以如果有人让你安静下来。
Hey settle down.
嘿，安静下来。
Settle down.
安静下来。
That means calm down.
意思是冷静下来。
Be quiet.
安静点。
You're too excited.
你太兴奋了。
Calm down.
冷静下来。
So you can use this with your kids maybe.
所以你可以对你的孩子用这个，也许。
Settle down.
安静下来。
We need to go.
我们得走了。
Come on.
快点。
Get in the car.
上车。
That's right.
没错。
So just kind of be quiet.
所以稍微安静点。
Be a little bit calmer.
冷静一点。
It's very very very important phrase especially if you're talking to younger people.
这是一个非常非常重要的短语，尤其是当你和年轻人说话时。
Okay.
好的。
And well of course when you're talking about sex with teenagers or younger people everyone's
当然，当你和青少年或年轻人谈论性时，每个人都会
laughing and giggling because it's such a weird thing for them.
笑个不停，因为这对他们来说是一件很奇怪的事。
And the teacher said I really want you to take this class seriously.
老师说我真的很希望你们认真对待这门课。
Okay so take this class seriously.
好的，所以认真对待这门课。
This comes from a sentence structure that's very very important.
这来自一个非常重要的句子结构。
To take something seriously.
认真对待某事。
I take my studies very seriously.
我非常认真地对待我的学习。
Or you guys should take this class seriously.
或者你们应该认真对待这门课。
It's important.
这很重要。
It means listen.
意思是听着。
Pay attention.
注意听。
This is important and you need to know this.
这很重要，你需要知道这个。
It's a way it's kind of a way to instruct someone to really pay attention.
这是一种指导某人真正注意的方式。
That's right.
没错。
Or what if you say I want you to take me seriously.
或者如果你说我希望你认真对待我。
That means I want you to really think about what I'm saying and not just talk to me like
那意味着我希望你真正思考我说的话，而不是像
a you know like I don't really understand what's going on.
我不太明白怎么回事那样跟我说话。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So to take something seriously is the structure.
所以“认真对待某事”是这个结构。
Now moving on to our final phrase.
现在进入我们最后一个短语。
When we were talking again about contraceptives we talked about avoiding pregnancy and we
当我们再次谈论避孕时，我们讨论了避免怀孕，我们
have a phrase that we use called unwanted pregnancy.
有一个短语叫意外怀孕。
Okay so pregnancy is what happens when someone gets pregnant.
好的，怀孕就是某人怀孕时发生的情况。
They're going to have a baby.
她们要生孩子了。
But an unwanted pregnancy is a certain kind of pregnancy.
但意外怀孕是一种特定的怀孕类型。
It means when someone did not plan to get pregnant or did not want to get pregnant.
意思是某人没有计划怀孕或不想怀孕。
So want unwanted is the opposite of wanted.
所以“不想要的”是“想要的”的反义词。
It means like it was an accident.
意思是这是个意外。
Right.
对。
So you wouldn't really say an accidental pregnancy because it you know.
所以你通常不会说“意外怀孕”，因为你知道。
It's still a kid.
它仍然是个孩子。
Exactly.
没错。
So you didn't want to get pregnant but you did.
所以你不想怀孕，但你怀了。
That's why we say unwanted pregnancy.
这就是为什么我们说意外怀孕。
Or you'll hear very often condoms help prevent unwanted pregnancy or the pill helps prevent
或者你经常听到避孕套有助于预防意外怀孕，或者避孕药有助于预防
unwanted pregnancy.
意外怀孕。
That's right.
没错。
Okay so a lot of interesting stuff there.
好的，那里有很多有趣的内容。
I think it's worthwhile for us to listen to our dialogue for one last time.
我觉得我们值得再听一遍对话。
All right settle down everyone.
好了，大家安静下来。
As part of this school's curriculum we'll be covering sex ed this week.
作为学校课程的一部分，这周我们将讲性教育。
Oh boy yeah.
哦，天哪。
Now I want everyone to take this class seriously.
现在我希望大家认真对待这门课。
Sexual education is very important and I want you to ask as many questions as you can think
性教育非常重要，我希望你们尽可能多地提问。
of.
Remember there are no stupid questions here.
记住，这里没有愚蠢的问题。
Miss Carlton what exactly is sexual education?
卡尔顿老师，性教育到底是什么？
Are you going to teach us like Kama Sutra and stuff like that?
你会教我们像《爱经》之类的东西吗？
No Jason that's not actually what sex ed is.
不，杰森，那不是性教育的内容。
Basically we will talk about sexually transmitted diseases, contraceptives and how the male
基本上，我们会讨论性传播疾病、避孕以及男性和
and female bodies work.
女性身体如何运作。
My older sister is in college and she takes what she and her friends call the pill.
我姐姐在上大学，她和她朋友吃一种叫避孕药的东西。
I never really understood what that is but I know it has to do with sex or something.
我一直不太明白那是什么，但我知道和性有关。
Good point Jason.
说得好，杰森。
This will be the topic of our first class contraceptives.
这将是我们第一节课的主题：避孕。
As you mentioned the pill is one of the many that exist.
正如你提到的，避孕药是众多避孕方法之一。
The birth control pill is taken daily by a woman in order to prevent unwanted pregnancy
避孕药是女性每天服用的，用来预防意外怀孕，
but it does not protect her from contracting STDs from an infected person.
但它不能保护她免受感染者的性病传染。
Another popular method is using condoms.
另一种流行的方法是使用避孕套。
This is probably the best method if you have sex since it not only prevents a woman from
如果你有性生活，这可能是最好的方法，因为它不仅能防止女性
getting pregnant but also protects you from STDs.
怀孕，还能保护你免受性病。
Yes Jason?
杰森，你说？
What are condoms made out of?
避孕套是用什么做的？
How is it exactly that a woman gets pregnant?
女性到底是怎么怀孕的？
Condoms are usually made out of an elastic material called latex.
避孕套通常由一种叫乳胶的弹性材料制成。
As for your other question, that's a whole new class.
至于你的另一个问题，那是全新的一节课。
Alright so coming back, we obviously didn't cover all forms of contraception and forms
好了，回到正题，我们显然没有涵盖所有避孕方式和
of protecting yourself against STDs but I remember very clearly in school when we talked
保护自己免受性病的方法，但我清楚地记得在学校讨论这个时，
about this, they said the best protection, the best way to not get pregnant or to get
他们说最好的保护，最好的避免怀孕或得性病的方法是
STDs is celibacy.
禁欲。
That's right.
没错。
Celibacy is not having any sex.
独身就是不发生任何性行为。
When I was in school they said the safest sex is no sex because there's always a little
我上学的时候，他们说过最安全的性行为就是不发生性行为，因为总是有一点
bit of danger.
风险。
And so this is something that I think they tell a lot of young people to scare them but
所以我觉得这是他们用来吓唬很多年轻人的说法，但
there is some truth to it.
其中也有一些道理。
Yeah of course.
当然是的。
Now what do you think about this topic?
那你对这个问题怎么看？
Do you think it's worthwhile and we should teach children sexual education or many people
你觉得值得吗？我们应该教孩子性教育，还是很多人
protest against it and say this is wrong, we shouldn't be giving kids condoms when they're
反对它，说这是不对的，我们不应该在孩子们
in high school?
上高中时给他们避孕套？
Well personally I think that kids in most parts of the world will have sex whether or
嗯，我个人认为，在世界大部分地区，无论你告不告诉他们不要发生性行为，
not you tell them not to.
孩子们都会发生。
And so because of that, because everyone's going to, there are always going to be people
正因为如此，因为每个人都会尝试，总有人
trying it, I think it's important to inform students and inform kids who are in high school
会去试，我认为重要的是要让学生和高中生了解
of options and of safety and of important health measures because otherwise you risk
选择、安全措施和重要的健康措施，否则你就有
unwanted pregnancies and you risk people getting these very serious diseases like AIDS.
意外怀孕的风险，以及人们感染像艾滋病这样严重疾病的风险。
That's right.
没错。
I think it is a very important topic.
我认为这是一个非常重要的话题。
Some countries or some places even within the United States are a little bit more conservative
有些国家或地方，甚至在美国境内，比其他的更保守一些，
than others and so many times they are against this type of education but I've actually encountered
所以很多时候他们反对这种教育，但我实际上遇到过
people who never received sexual education and well until they were maybe like 18 they
从未接受过性教育的人，直到他们大概18岁时，
thought they can get pregnant by a kiss.
还以为接吻就能怀孕。
So I think that's one of the dangers.
所以我认为这是其中一个危险。
Obviously there are both sides to this issue and we're curious to know what you think.
显然，这个问题有两面性，我们很好奇你的看法。
Do you think that sex ed should be a course or should be something that people talk about
你认为性教育应该是一门课程，还是应该成为人们在学校、
in schools, in high school or in college?
高中或大学里讨论的话题？
Do they do this in your home country?
在你的祖国，他们这样做吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Another orientation of the
另一个方向是